<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stories about patterns</title>
    <atom:link href="http://www.franc.ly/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://www.franc.ly</link>
    <description>Quantitative and qualitative storytelling</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>A weekly review process</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Weekly%20review%20process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Weekly%20review%20process/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m implementing a personal weekly review process to help manage projects I’m working on, keep a log of ideas and delegate things out of my head, because I basically say yes to &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too many things. I’m literally scheduling time for this. To start, I’m putting 2h 30min a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is based on a conversation with and an idea by &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncommonplaces.com/about-ida-benedetto/&quot;&gt;Ida Benedetto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor the projects you are working on.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List what you’re working on. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review, update, throw on to backlog remove.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detail tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allocate time for documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can I open-source about what I’m making?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note personal goal on each of these projects (including actual work work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep a log of where projects stand. Are all of these really simultaneously manageable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep a three phase list&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 - This project will get work this week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 - This project is in a planning phase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 - This project is in a completely speculative phase. It may happen, most likely not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your ideas in check.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 min brainstorm: what have you been thinking on this last week? All sorts of ideas, personal, professional and all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up after yourself, in both the physical and digital worlds.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean your mail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure email is at 0 too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List things to do IRL: DMV, presents, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage mid-term calendar&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review your calendar - What’s happened in the last two weeks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review your calendar - What’s happening in the next three weeks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review your work process&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the review process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Emerging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Emerging/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading Jo Freeman &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.historyisaweapon.com/defcon1/tyrstruct.html&quot;&gt;“The Tyranny of Structurelessness”&lt;/a&gt;, portions of Alexander Galloway’s &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt; and other texts on decentralization, hierarchies and power structures for &lt;a href=&quot;http://allisonburtch.net/&quot;&gt;Allison Burtch&lt;/a&gt; workshop at SFPC, I think about recent democratic uprisings and the genesis of social movements that we’ve witnessed in recent years and their struggle with finding an articulate structure appropriate for the challenges of now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Emerging/structureless.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sturcturelessness&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Structurelessness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the 2008 financial crisis, the economical policies implemented by political bodies to “mitigate” the effects of the crisis (as if it was some sort of weather disaster) revealed deep gaps in democracy quality in a lot of countries. These policies had specific effects in the south of Europe. In the case of Spain, these policies were heavily intertwined with steps taken by the political and business elites to maintain their position as &lt;em&gt;extractive caste&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, a wave of technological social tools has been readily available for those movements that sprung after the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galloway’s &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt; is a good resource to understand TCP/IP protocols on the Internet as this illusion of a horizontal, leveled field in communications where the individual hosts self-organize and hierarchical power structures of the past are no longer applicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analogously, communication tools have provided an illusion of structurelessness and horizontality in social and political movements emerging in the recent times that can act as a double-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These movements (Tahrir, 15M, Occupy) that gained relevance after the crash found themselves with a power for organization that could easily outdo the articulation of their discourse. An ongoing challenge they had to overcome was precisely the right structure that would allow this articulation and some capacity for execution without compromising equality principles that characterized their existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the powerful ideas on Freeman’s writing is that collectives can &lt;em&gt;not not have a structure&lt;/em&gt;. If there is no defined structure and process to question it, the movement is abandoning itself to an informal sturcture that replicate non-explicit power dynamics between members, which tend to be fertile field for demogagocial and brute-force sequestration of the movement. Revolutions that go awry tend to fail here, when the uprising outpaces the articulation of a functioning structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movements like the Egyptian Revolution in 2011, the 15M Movement in Spain or OccupyWallStreet in the US spent a significant amount of energy and resources in defining the structure of their own movement as well as the articulation of a common discourse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Emerging/informal_structure.png&quot; alt=&quot;Informal sturcture&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Informal structure&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got somewhat involved in the 15M movement when I could go, and followed very closely from distance and participated when I could online. I also followed OWS quite closely. In the Spanish movement, the lack of political experience of a big part of its participants made the need for debates around structure much more explicit. In parallel to political debates, and attempts to articulate specific demands around a common discourse, the debate around structure, leardership and collective decision-making processes in the movement was (and still it) one of the most active. Some of these, particularly in Spain (with the PAH, Guanyem or Podemos), have chrystalized in new political entities that embody this constant readjustment and questioning the right balance between structure and equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Emerging/formal_structure.png&quot; alt=&quot;Formal sturcture&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Formal structure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Whitney is getting me started on oF</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/John%20Whitney%20is%20getting%20me%20started%20on%20oF/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/John%20Whitney%20is%20getting%20me%20started%20on%20oF/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John Whitney was considered one of the fathers of computer animation. His early work is almost purely mechanical, literally, and he set the foundations for more digital work later on. Most of his stuff is slightly psychedelic &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At an animation workshop at SFPC on openFrameworks with &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesystemis.com/&quot;&gt;Zach Lieberman&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve reviewed some of Whitney’s work and taken it as inspiration for some experiments. Since I’m exploring particle systems and swarm behavior, this is a piece I was looking into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 500px; margin: 0 auto; margin-bottom: 1.52em&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/110486548&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;369&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s a still of the original I was trying to replicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./original.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ursula K Leguin on Utopia</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Ursula%20K%20Leguin%20on%20Utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Ursula%20K%20Leguin%20on%20Utopia/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some intersting quotes from some readings we’ve been doing by Ursula K LeGuin’s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-noneuclidean-view-of-california-as-a-cold-place-to-be&quot;&gt;A noneuclidean view of California as a cold place to be&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am offered the Grand Inquisitor’s choice. Will you choose freedom without happiness, or happiness without freedom? The only answer one can make, I think is: No.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With all our self-consciousness, we have very little sense of where we live, where we are right here right now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It seems that the utopian imagination is trapped, like capitalism and industrialism and the human population, in a one-way future consisting only of growth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[The utopia of the Grand Inquisitor] is the product of the &lt;strong&gt;euclidean mind&lt;/strong&gt; (a phrase Dostoyevsky used often), which is obsessed by the idea of regulating of regulating all life by reason and bringing happiness to man whatever the cost.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utopia has been euclidean, it has been European, and it has been masculine. I am trying to suggest, in an evasive, distrustful, untrustworthy fashion, and as obscurely as I can, that our final loss of faith in that radiant sandcastle may enable our eyes to adjust to a dimmer light and in it perceive another kind of utopia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[We must believe] that through the exercise of their reason men can control and in major ways alter for the better their social environment… One must have faith of a kind that our history has made completely inaccessible.”
&lt;em&gt;Bob Elliott&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Totalitarianism is not only hell, but also the dream of paradise — the age old dream of a world where everybody would dream in harmony, united by a single common will and faith, without secrets from one another… If totalitarianism did not exploit these archetypes, which are deep inside us all and rooted deep in all religions, it could never attract so many people, especially during the early phases of its existence. “
&lt;em&gt;Milan Kundera&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The purer, the more euclidean the reason that builds a utopia, the greater its self-destructive capacity. I submit that our lack of faith in the benevolence of reason as the controlling power is well founded.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Lévi-Strauss [makes the distinction][…] between the &lt;em&gt;hot&lt;/em&gt; societies, which have appeared since the Neolithic Revolution, and in which &lt;em&gt;differentiations between castes and between classes are urged without cease, in order that social change and energy may be extracted from them&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;em&gt;cold&lt;/em&gt; societies, self-limited, whose historical temperature is pretty near zero.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Talking about &lt;em&gt;The Dispossessed&lt;/em&gt;] “Anarchism rejects the identification of civilization with the state, and the identification of power with coercion; against the inherent violence of the &lt;em&gt;hot&lt;/em&gt; society it asserts the value of such antisocial behavior as the general refusal of women to bear arms in war; and other coyote devices.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[This is mine: What is she talking about? Women are more prominent leaders, as well as fighters, in anarchist movements than in any other political movement (see Spanish Revolution of 1936). I must be misunderstanding what she meant with this paragraph.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They are assailed by too many new things ever to find the depths in the old before it has gone by. The rush of life past them they call progress, though it is too rapid for them to move with it. Man remains the same, baffled and astonished, with a heap of new things around him but gone before he knows them. Men may live many sorts of lives, and this they call &lt;em&gt;opportunity&lt;/em&gt;,and believe opportunity good without ever examining any one of those lives to know if it is good. We have fewer ways of life and most of us never know but one.” 
&lt;em&gt;Lord Dorn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think we’re ever going to get to utopia again by going forward, but only roundabout or sideways.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-left-hand-of-darkness&quot;&gt;The left hand of darkness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I talk about the gods, I am an atheist. But I am an artist too, and therefore a liar. Distrust everything I say. I am telling the truth. The only truth I can understand or express is, logically defined, a lie. Psychologically defined, a symbol. Aesthetically defined, a metaphor.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A life inventory</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/A%20life%20inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/A%20life%20inventory/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t generally celebrate my birthday. Although I enjoy other people’s parties, I feel self-conscious throwing a party for myself, and don’t tell anyone. Some people remember sometimes, and it’s nice, but it tends to go quite unnoticed, which I’m totally ok with. I’m actually enjoying getting older, but throwing a party for myself doesn’t feel representative of what I feel when &lt;code&gt;myAge++&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do, however, tend to find meaning in rituals and I like stories, and since I’m turning 30 now, I’ve been telling people about it a bit more than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I’ve had a blast in my 20s. The decade has been really good with me, and I’ve been blessed with all sorts of adventures and experiences, too many to enumerate here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of celebrating my 30th birthday, I felt like celebrating my 20s. Instead of celebrating by receiving a party, or by receiving presents, and since at this point I have people scattered all over the world, I decided to celebrate by doing a bit of a life inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to go through a list of all the people who have impacted my life in one way or another, and send a letter giving thanks. It feels much more correct to celebrate by thanking people who’ve made my 20s happen than thanking myself for, huh, existing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been an interesting exercise. I couldn’t write to &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt;, it would have been a monumental task. I tried to be honest with myself and write not only to people who I really felt like celebrating together, but also to people who I felt a bit uncomfortable with, people who did impact my life even when I did not impact theirs in any meaningful way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, I wrote a letter to my nephew to be kept unopened until the day he turns 20, or November 11th 2033, with some of the lessons I’ve learned during these 10 amazing years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/A%20life%20inventory/letters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Letters!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commodified socialism for the wealthy</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Commodified%20socialism%20for%20the%20wealthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Commodified%20socialism%20for%20the%20wealthy/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very cautious with the current use of the idea of the “creative class” by the establishment. I find it sometimes loaded with social engineering perversion, used as a substitute for true artistic experimentation and political involvement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creatives are artists that have made themselves digestible by “innovative” companies, therefore ditching anything coming with the spirit that is political or socially rebellious, and is one of the big factors that catalyzes gentrification. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cities and real estate development agencies use “creative class” because it sounds better than “white young college-educated people willing to work for little money under the promise of artistic fulfillment”. They (we) are indeed white, culturally upper-middle class in a precarious financial situation, which is a different manifestation of a class of the ones traditionally thought of, but one class division after all that comes with a very specific set of demons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, and I talk about NY which is the only thing I know, nightlife is becoming less transgressive and less dangerous to the establishment, and neighborhoods and venues are every day more heavily race and class-divided. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Full disclosure: I work for the marketing team of a tech company in Manhattan.).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The creative class</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Creative%20class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Creative%20class/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very cautious with the current use of the idea of the “creative class” by the establishment. I find it sometimes loaded with social engineering perversion, used as a substitute for true artistic experimentation and political involvement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creatives are artists that have made themselves digestible by “innovative” companies, therefore ditching anything coming with the spirit that is political or socially rebellious, and is one of the big factors that catalyzes gentrification. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cities and real estate development agencies use “creative class” because it sounds better than “white young college-educated people willing to work for little money under the promise of artistic fulfillment”. They (we) are indeed white, culturally upper-middle class in a precarious financial situation, which is a different manifestation of a class of the ones traditionally thought of, but one class division after all that comes with a very specific set of demons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, and I talk about NY which is the only thing I know, nightlife is becoming less transgressive and less dangerous to the establishment, and neighborhoods and venues are every day more heavily race and class-divided. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Full disclosure: I work for the marketing team of a tech company in Manhattan.).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the right questions to ask</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Questions%20to%20ask/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Questions%20to%20ask/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first few weeks at the School for Poetic Computation have been overwhelming with awesomeness. There was a moment last Wednesday, two weeks in, when I felt very heavily saturated with new inputs and ideas. I started feeling some anxiety trying to find the balance between learning and production, between learning and theory and capacity to execute. Or even understanding what I wanted to get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the difficulty of that is the added handicap of never been to art school or fully pursued a purely artistic intention or exploration in my projects in such an open ended way before. This has me dealing with unlearning certain types of mental processes, being unsure about the ways I should pursue some of these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I exposed this to some of the students in the school, and was happy to discover that it was not an uncommon feeling. It seems that this is part of the process, to go through all of these doors being open, all these new constructs to make and struggle your way through their digestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ablersite.org/about/&quot;&gt;Sara Hendren&lt;/a&gt; came to give a talk at the school. She is an artist and researcher who works at the intersection of design and engineer, and does a lot of work on communication and journalism, generally around the idea of assistive technology. She has a strong thesis that I think is well summarized by the motto &lt;em&gt;all technology is assistive technology&lt;/em&gt;, which is the title of a popular post she wrote (but I can’t find now, I promise to update when I do).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had an incredible capacity for precise, explanatory and very powerful language, which may be a consequence of the complexity of the issue she’s taken as central to her work and how identity and language are a strong factor into how that topic is perceived. She presented a lot of projects that explored topics of her own research and interests, and the way she framed the questions that these projects were looking to answer really resonated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a short chat with her the day after, and this became especially clear. After the chat, I felt that I was asking questions about what I was looking for, asking the questions that resonated with me in a way that allowed me to have a framework of reference by which to prioritize work and filter inputs. It’s given me a direction of exploration. I feel I have a powerful tool in my hands that I can use to guide myself. It’s now a matter of correctly framing the question and materializing it into specific rules that guide my creation and learning. I’m waiting to have that question better framed to explore some of this ideas more in depth in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pong experiment</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/The%20pong%20experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/The%20pong%20experiment/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1991, in a computer graphics conference called SIGGRAPH celebrated in California, Loren Carpenter, founder of Pixar Animation Studios, did a very interesting experiment in collective action and decision making using the audience as participants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 500px; margin: 0 auto&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/78043173&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swarm</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Swarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Swarm/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Swarm - &lt;em&gt;noun \ˈswȯrm\ &lt;/em&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A large number of animate or inanimate things massed together and usually in motion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swarm behavior:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collective behaviour exhibited by animals of similar size which aggregate together and are in motion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regarding mathematical modelling, an emergent behaviour arising from simple rules that are followed by individuals and does not involve any central coordination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology as delegation</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Technology%20as%20delegation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Technology%20as%20delegation/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sometimes think of technology, in its broader sense, as all of those things humans do to delegate some of their abilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By delegating, by externalizing some of human’s innate abilities, we are abstracting them. Once these functions are abstracted, they can be manipulated. So in a way, by delegating abilities into devices or objects, technology allows us to abstract, redefine and manipulate our own abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20120206001457/http://www.framejournal.net/interview/14/belinda-barnet&quot;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;, Belinda Barnet provides the example of Plato, who opposed the introduction of books into the educational experience because it would ‘&lt;em&gt;implant forgetfulness in [men’s] souls&lt;/em&gt;‘. Indeed, by relying more on books, instead of memorizing thousands of verses, students most likely reduced their mnemonic capacities. The &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to memorize many facts was not there anymore. It delegated the retention of information to a device that could not only store enormous amounts of information, but also allowed to be distributed easier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common introduction of books probably hurt some aspects of thought and the learning experience as it was understood until that moment. By having a thought grow and brew in one’s subconscious, some hidden functions take place below the surface allowing the evolution of that thought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since scripture is a way of abstracting memory and communication, and extend these abilities beyond their time and space constraints, this allows all sorts of other manipulations. By this &lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt; (ha) trick, it allowed philosophy, literature, science and every realm of human thought to evolve. And the gains are easier to see than the loses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some of the mental functions we are delegating now to computers? What are some of the processes we are allowing to happen in the future by manipulating abstractions of our own abilities? What is the way technology is designed and implemented today inflicting in the way we understand learning and the human experience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scholastic.com/browse/article.jsp?id=5&quot;&gt;Face to Face: Alan Kay Still Waiting for the Revolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Mindstorms-Children-Computers-Powerful-Ideas/dp/0465046746&quot;&gt;Mindstorms&lt;/a&gt; by Seymour Papert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r36NNGzNvjo&quot;&gt;If you could have what you wanted, what would it be like?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letters</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Letters/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I sent a few letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll explain later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Letters/letters.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Letters&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overwhelming</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Overwhelming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Overwhelming/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’m feeling a bit overwhelmed. By awesomeness, but definitely overwhelmed. At SFPC, we’ve been in touch with so many ideas, experiences, languages, that it is already all a bit difficult to absorb and process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part for me is not only that, but the fact that absorbing all these new inputs has my mind flying around like a butterfly from idea to idea, without really committing to any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that’s what it’s supposed to be. I can acknowledge the value of focusing on learning, processing, exercising around a whole lot of ideas, getting your mind trained into thinking and reflecting about all of this. There is a whole lot of value I’m already feeling on thinking about systems in a playful, creative way. I find myself &lt;em&gt;unlearning&lt;/em&gt; the way I usually think about projects, and it feels very inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I feel a little anxious when I see my mind wandering so much and can sense the possibility of not even &lt;em&gt;producing&lt;/em&gt; anything solid at the end that I can present to myself as a tangible output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to list out what was realistic to expect from SFPC in those terms, and was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unrealistic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get proficient in any new language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produce one, two, three pieces of middle complexity to show, when you’ve never actually worked in that context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Realistic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get in touch with a whole lot of languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to think conceptually about computing, about programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a hang of other angles to this (experience design, performance art, installations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produce a couple of proof of concepts of realms you never actually produced anything for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a lot of writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document artists, tools, career paths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make honest, intersting, genuine connections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting out with Arduino</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Starting%20out%20on%20Arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Starting%20out%20on%20Arduino/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been looking for excuses to learn Arduino for a long time. My common regular work has barely anything to do with the physical world, and I am not an engineer, so I’ve been putting it off for an indefinite amount of time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing some of his projects and expertise, I asked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.extrasleepy.com&quot;&gt;Andrew Kleindolph&lt;/a&gt;, an interaction designer and technology teacher I’ve had the pleasure to meet at SFPC, for some ways into it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some resources I’m looking into right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.adafruit.com/category/learn-arduino&quot;&gt;Do these starting with lesson 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.sparkfun.com/tutorials/connecting-arduino-to-processing&quot;&gt;Connecting Arudino to Processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the main Arduino site: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arduino.cc/en/Guide/HomePage&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/HomePage&quot;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;And here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Arduino-Cookbook-Michael-Margolis/dp/1449313876/ref=sr_1_5?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1413298471&amp;amp;sr=1-5&amp;amp;keywords=Arduino&quot;&gt;good book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more advanced stuff, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adafruit.com/product/1557&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; seems to work great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it’s only a matter of finding good stuff to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Starting%20out%20on%20Arduino/arduinouno.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arduino Uno board&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stupid projects</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Stupid%20projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Stupid%20projects/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Nothing useless can be truly beautiful.”&lt;/em&gt;
—&lt;strong&gt;William Morris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects that you take on your free time, as opposed to comissioned projects, can be of different sorts. Some are born with the goal to explore and research topics without a specific output to produce. Some are born with a purely artistic or even aesthetic intention. Others are totally an excuse to learn new tools, methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this last type, I find it useful to imagine completely stupid and missionless projects by piling up pieces of things you’d like to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say I have a serious project in mind. My goal involves using &lt;strong&gt;Twitter bots&lt;/strong&gt; that can publicize and create awareness on a social project (like stop-and-frisk). I’m doing some research looking for public data, looking for an angle in, but I haven’t quite figured out a way to make something useful for that cause. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good is to step back and instead of staying in the seriousness when your point is not well defined, let’s do something to make sure all the pieces are well tied together. Let’s say I also want to learn a little bit of &lt;strong&gt;Node.js&lt;/strong&gt;. And just for the fun of it, let’s say I’ve been wanting to learn how to use a couple of features of the &lt;strong&gt;SoundCloud API&lt;/strong&gt;, to keep track of my Likes (because SoundCloud’s UI is beautiful but not very reliable) as well as explore some designy features of SVG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those things together don’t seem to make much sense, but I’m still going to come up with a way to link them as an excuse to learn. This is what is technically referred to as a &lt;em&gt;stupid&lt;/em&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stupid projects are the best because they put little pressure on being coherent, smart and making solid points, and allow you to focus on the technical aspects and make little tutorials out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s a list of the pieces I’m trying to pile up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a Twitter bot using Node. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apcoder.com/2013/10/03/twitter-bot-20-minutes-node-js/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;‘s a super simple way to do that with a module called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ttezel/twit&quot;&gt;twit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently to create a Twitter account you need a unique email address (which, if you own a domain, shouldn’t be an issue) and a unique telephone number. Which is an issue, because I only own a cell phone (I know, weird right?). To give a twitter bot Write access via a centralized twitter account, follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://dghubble.com/blog/posts/twitter-app-write-access-and-bots/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suspect this last thing allows for the &lt;em&gt;automation&lt;/em&gt; of creating twitter accounts (for noble missions like spam and fake accounts), but this is not my goal, so I won’t explore that for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Node script will check once a day whether I have liked new shit on SoundCloud using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/soundcloud-node&quot;&gt;this module&lt;/a&gt;, and scrape that song down using a module called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dmotz/soundscrape&quot;&gt;SoundScrape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sebpiq/node-web-audio-api&quot;&gt;Node implementation of the HTML5’s Web Audio API&lt;/a&gt;, I’ll load the data of the audio file, sample it and draw a Time Domain area chart as SVG, apply a blur effect to a point it’s totally unrecognizeable and tweet the image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Stupid%20projects/soundscape.png&quot; alt=&quot;Soundscape&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few notes on modular Javascript</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Modular%20javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Modular%20javascript/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So when you start writing your first large applications, all the material and documentation you will find will tell you to write &lt;em&gt;modular&lt;/em&gt; code, that is, use the module pattern for absolutely everything. This, they say, will give you great control over private and public methods without polluting the global namespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is totally true and something that understanding early in the process will save you a lot of refactoring time and debugging nightmares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it’s not immediately obvious to a person who’s learning to code how the structure needs to be layed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a module:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; MODULE = (&lt;span class=&quot;function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;params&quot;&gt;(myModule)&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; _variable = &lt;span class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;45&lt;/span&gt;;

    myModule.getVariable = &lt;span class=&quot;function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;params&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; {&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; _variable;
    }

    &lt;span class=&quot;keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; myModule;

}(myModule || {}));
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a module with one very clear function, make a non-public variable within the module accessible outside the &lt;a href=&quot;http://javascriptissexy.com/understand-javascript-closures-with-ease/&quot;&gt;closure&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For convention, I noted the variable as private by using an leading underscore ‘_’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, when you’re dealing with a site that is likely to need more than a handful of lines and likely to lean towards OOP as much as Javascript can get, dividing functionality in modules should be done from the start, no matter whether you’re using a third-party framework or creating your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to organize your code while you’re writing, the best you can do is to have every module in a different file, and use something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.requirejs.org&quot;&gt;RequireJS&lt;/a&gt; to orderly load them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of the best articles I’ve found to understand how to organize and properly write modular code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codethinked.com/preparing-yourself-for-modern-javascript-development&quot;&gt;Preparing yourself for modern JS development&lt;/a&gt;, by Justin Etheredge (&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to start here!&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jblotus.com/2013/01/13/common-javascript-gotchas/&quot;&gt;Common JS gotchas&lt;/a&gt;, by James Fuller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adequatelygood.com/JavaScript-Module-Pattern-In-Depth.html&quot;&gt;Javascript Module Pattern in depth&lt;/a&gt; (The most complete and “aha”-inducing article ever to be written about JS), by Ben cherry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wishes for 2014</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Wishes%20for%202014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Wishes%20for%202014/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopt “joy and kindness” as my motto.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ll hear a lot more about B Corps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ll collectively stop using the expression “change the world” in tech when it’s not accurate. In case you’re hesitating, it’s most likely not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will all make an extra effort to simply not have an opinion about how should anybody live her life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some new music will be amazing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New companies will get me as excited as Kickstarter, Twitter or Kiva did a few years back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ll be extra vigilant to point out when our behavior is reinforcing any type of discrimination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gender issues and sexism will see a real involvement from men.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s really not part of the sharing economy, but rather the renting economy (I’m looking at you AirBnB), will be called so and the actual sharing economy will be left alone. Just to be clear, AirBnB is totally awesome, but it’s just not called sharing if you’re paying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some company will emerge that challenges Apple and I’ll be able to reduce my absolute dependency to their products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will stop finding “tuna” under “vegetable sandwiches”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Spanish state will stop sucking big time and start behaving like a 21st century democracy good enough for European standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech media will start doing actual journalism and stop doing free publicity for the big players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ll stop talking about Edward Snowden and Glenn Greenwald and actually start talking about privacy and accountability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ll collectively stop using the word “hipster”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's to joy and kindness.</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/thankfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/thankfulness/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is just a ride.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this one has been amazing. This one has been one of those of being close to the core of the mystery of life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have all been part of this. Some of you, because you’re so deeply entrenched into what my life is, that my life would just not be a thing without you. Some of you, I just recently met and I may know very little about you. But I still have a big deal to thank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who just touched my life represent the largest, most beautiful mystery of what it means to be human. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that there actually is a ‘us’. There is a ‘all of us’ that we all feel in some hidden corner of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may think you aren’t doing anything altruistic. But you are. You are bringing on your most limited resources, your energy, your time, your space, your youth, smiles, creative energy. You acknowledge joy and other people’s happiness, you acknowledge and promote togetherness. You have the belief that increasing that is a noble endeavor worth being pursued, the endeavor to make life a wonderful adventure and this world one worth living in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have made me smile, dance, work, talk, think, travel, wonder, kiss, have sex, watch, read, write, draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have made me feel excited, loved, valued, marveled, challenged, lucky, excited, dumb, listened to, guilty, smart, confused and happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this means you believe in joy. You believe in kindness. You believe that we collectively decided to make this world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that, I thank you from the deepest corner of whatever it is that makes me me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on loving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And bring on 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I rennovated my site</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/newest-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/newest-site/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to do a lot more writing for a long time. Last year I redesigned my personal site and I ambitiously started two blogs, one for visualization ideas and tutorials, interaction and so on, which I called Patterns, and another for more free creative writing, which I called No Patterns. Both were self-hosted Wordpress. I adjusted the visual design and hosted them on together with the rest of my main site so it could be experience without friction once you had accessed it. And while I think it worked for a bit, both for me as a writer and for people who would visit it, I decided I needed to lower the barrier even more to get myself to write regularly. Either that, or integrate writing so much into my site that it would be embarrassing to not update regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I redesigned the whole site by using &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintersmith.io/&quot;&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jade-lang.com&quot;&gt;Jade&lt;/a&gt;, a Node templating engine. This allows me to have total control over my content and the architecture while being perfectly scalable and easy to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got rid of every social network widget or distraction. I wanted the reading experience to be as immersive as possible, even for the silliest things. I find myself more and more annoyed by distraction on the web, and wanted to work in the direction of cleaningness. If somebody really likes a text, tweeting the link is really not that difficult. And writing resonates with readers if they concentrate on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s great is that, in addition, Wintersmith supports &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Markdown is great for a variety of reasons, it’s really readable while you write and edit and you can forget about blog plaforms or worrying about CSS once it’s live. Furthermore, it’s perfect to create articles in a consistent fashion from a regular text editor, which will make it much easier to add writing to my site and have it organize by the date just like a blog platform would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is great because it’s intuitive and extremely readable while editing. Instead of tags, you’d use stuff like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Some title
==========
A slightly less important title
-------------------------------

Paragraphs are separated
by a blank line.

Text attributes *italic*,
**bold**, `monospace`.

Shopping list:

  * apples
  * oranges
  * pears

Numbered list:

  1. apples
  2. oranges
  3. pears
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some random things that happened in 2013</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/A%20year%20in%20review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/A%20year%20in%20review/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Met my nephew when he was 2 hours old. Such a trip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Randomly ran into people in Mexico City.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Met incredible artists in New York, New Orleans, Minneapolis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survived a week of trash collectors strike in Madrid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experienced a syndrome of Stendhal in Minorca. Again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missed my first flight, in Minneapolis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Danced off a snow blizzard in Brooklyn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started training capoeira seriously again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fell off my bike twice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started using Backbone.js.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turned 29.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved from Bedstuy to Bedstuy, stayed in Bedstuy, loved Bedstuy more than ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read books not written by Roberto Bolaño.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saw the sun going down behind Manhattan dancing on a Brooklyn rooftop with a bunch of adorable human beings and I get goosebumps just by remembering how beautiful it was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saw a bear in the wild at like 15 feet from me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a water pipe explode in the middle of the night in my room in Brooklyn and flood the whole thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Met beautiful unicorns and incredible people from all over the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attended Eyeo, Visualized and ITP Camp and get mesmerized, inspired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ditched a suitcase full of clothing on an airport because they were gonna make me chose between rebooking (and repaying) or boarding without luggage. Yes, it was Delta. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a spandex screen where you could pretty much literally touch visuals, on openFrameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took things less personal. Will still be working on that one in 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When I leave New York</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/when-I-leave-NY/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/when-I-leave-NY/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I leave New York, and I’ll find that new place for me, eventually I’ll look back at you in search of inspiration. And I’ll ask that memory to empower me, like you used to do with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave New York, I’ll think of you and the density of talent that I could meet in a weekend, the impossible stories, your diversity of faces and goals, and ways of loving, ways of aspiring, a diversity so deep that is invisible, like there are no patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave New York I won’t remember how hard you were with me in the first days, how hard you are with your kids, how hard you are with those confused, with those who hesitate. I’ll remember how a feeling of rejection can be transformed into individual freedom and confidence, how everything is subjective and nobody really knows how to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave my New York I’ll remember the excitement, the extremes, I’ll remember the obsessions, I’ll remember your photogenia and your vanity, I’ll remember your streets full of delusional dreams. I’ll remember your tough lessons, and how they worked, and I’ll see myself losing steam at times, and I’ll think of you and regain energy to keep going. ‘New York would not let me stop now’, I’ll tell myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave New York I’ll remember how relationships were so volatile and I’ll try to imagine what it would have been like to be a single girl in New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave New York, I will remember what it means to be hungry to do more, to go higher, to learn faster, what it means to be hungry for creation, for starting up, and what it means to be in the quest for something. I’ll remember what it means to be alone with your story to be written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave New York, everything will move slowly for a while, and I’ll remember my years with you as a fast sequence of snapshots, faces and places, and parties, and opportunities, and people to admire, and fucking assholes, and money, and weird-ass situations, and crazy people with nobody to help them, and my bike, and your smile on the subway, and hot coffee in a snowy winter Thursday, and dancing next to Gowanus canal on a sunny summer Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave New York, I’ll remember the most important lesson you taught me: that everything is just another story, and you only need to tell it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/when-I-leave-NY/snownyc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Snow NYC&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On working remotely</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/On%20working%20remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/On%20working%20remotely/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished a project that set a milestone in my work life. From start to finish, from the moment I planned the idea to the moment I sent the final version of it, I didn’t see a face of the people I was working for. I was working from New York for a crowdfunding site named Goteo, that operates in Spain. Besides how engaged with the project I felt, working remotely has been an incredibly interesting experience, and has helped me reflect about the nature of work today and possibilities to come. I’ll do more of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goteo is a crowdfunding site based in Spain, but it’s decentralized across the country. The team is formed by people working from Mallorca, Barcelona and Bilbao and decentralization is part of their DNA. They are incredibly passionate about what they do, and their plan is to create nodes of the site that operate autonomously from different locations and can have a better handle on local projects. They’re soon to add new nodes in Sevilla and Madrid. So it was the right type of organization to start en endeavor like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked so great that it made me think about what can be improved of the usual ways of working. Why are we so attached to a certain location when thinking about work? There are a whole lof of engineering and creative projects, and even some managerial tasks, that can be at least as well handed remotely as they can be on site. And especially in technology and some forms of art, there is no reason any more to keep forcing people to move from city to city every time they get a new job or start a new project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of the projects at Knewton, we use collaborative tools that can be used from anywhere. GitHub, Google Drive, JIRA, Confluence. Most of the communication around projects happen via email or chat, even when collaborators are in the office. Communication is critical for every collaborative project (was I not being obvious enough?), but I would say that some of the collaborative tools we use may actually increase the effectivity of communication beyond the effectivity of physical meetings in some aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not saying physical meetings are not important. Some ideas are better discussed in person and some meetings really do push projects forward. But, let’s face it, most don’t, especially after the definition phase. When the roadmap is clear, stop talking and start moving, and communicate about facts, not about ideas. There are more productive ways to merge ideas and lead discussions, keep each other accountable can work better with tools specifically designed for that purpose. Just think of applying version-control to every part of the design, building and implementation of a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For companies, allowing their employees to work remotely means a bigger ability to attract talent anywhere, and adapting better to the needs of their most valued workers. For employers, a more flexible situation means having access to a larger landscape of opportunities and being able to lead a life more adjusted with each one’s needs and aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the human perspective, being able to work remotely can improve your productivity substantially, but also your quality of life. It allows you to have the schedule that better suits your own rhythms. I’m an extremely morning person (I know, right?), and not having to go to work until 9 or 10, and having to stay beyond 7 does not really work for me. Why would I waste my most productive hours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, it allows you to work from anywhere where your work is better, be it a coffee shop, a co-working space or home. My ideal choice is a coffee shop. I hate isolation, and I love the feeling of other people working in different things around me. A co-working space would work great, I assume, I’ve just never tried it. I don’t like working from home, but I know a lot of people do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are complications. There needs to be a clearly stated process for accountability, and an effort from all parts to keep very, very active the communication channel. The isolation factor doesn’t really work for everybody and some projects need a constant interaction. Also, some creativity processes need people to interact with similar inputs and ideas constantly. Generating new and useful ideas means putting together a lot of partially shared unfinished thoughts and reactions to the same inputs. This is difficult to mimic without physical interaction, but it is compensated by the easy access to more creative inputs from other sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, I was living in Berlin and met a Canadian programmer who had just arrived to the city. He had just moved from Colombia, where he had spent some time living, and was planning to stay for a few months in the city. He had been working the whole time for employers that were never based where he was. That struck me so bad I promised myself to try at least to go in the same direction. It looks like it’s taking some time, but I’m getting slowly closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working remotely does not mean that it doesn’t matter where you are working from. If I was not in NYC I would not have met the people I’ve met, I would not have come across certain opportunities and would have certainly made decisions differently. Where you physically are matters especially because you’re going to be in touch with ideas you would not see otherwise. It makes you interact with different mind sets, which is always good creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A documentary about creative coding</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/A%20documentary%20about%20creative%20coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/A%20documentary%20about%20creative%20coding/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;div style=&quot;margin: 0 auto; width: 500px&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/60735314&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/60735314&quot;&gt;Hello World! Processing&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/ultralab&quot;&gt;Ultra_Lab&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On why NYC is not a hedonistic place</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/On%20why%20NYC%20is%20not%20a%20hedonistic%20place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/On%20why%20NYC%20is%20not%20a%20hedonistic%20place/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve interacted with work culture in several countries, but strongly interacted with it in three: Spain, Germany and the US, via their least representative cities, Barcelona, Berlin and New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York is the least hedonistic of these places, and it’s not even close. First let me tell you that I love New York and I’m very thankful for a lot of things I’ve learned here. Hedonsim is not the only school of thought I enjoy, and so this is not supposed to be offensive. It’s just a fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you why I think so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By hedonistic I mean a place where people’s behavior is driven by pleasure, the sooner and more intense the better. Hedonism can be moderate, for example, when slowly spending your afternoon walking by your neighborhood with friends from coffee shop to book store, lie on a park, talk about life and so on, or more extreme, for example, anything related to club culture, drugs, uncommitted casual sex and other fun stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York does not thrive in neither. Of course, you can do any of those things, but the city is not configured so that leading any of those activities is easy nor status-increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, the city is optimized for work. You just have to take a look at the subway system to realize that subways are specifically designed to take people from where they live to work and back (from the outer boroughs to Manhattan and back, but not within borrough).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, there is a judgmental attitude about what you do with your life, what you work on, why you are interesting, and this pressure make people work harder than elsewhere. People that don’t have a clear professional goal are continuously sanctioned in conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, there is a strong financial pressure. The fact that everything is expensive and difficult makes you want to make more money and if you’re not Warren Buffet, you’ll basically do that by working. More.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some aspects of hedonism that are present. Relationships are more volatile, so meeting new people is a constant. Making new friends is easier, but relationships are more superficial. This adds a notion of hedonism, but subtracts from the fact that deeper layers are never reached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One common response that people have to counter the idea of NYC as non-hedonistic is the fact that you can get anything you want at any time you want. You can get Korean-Mexican food at 430 am on a Tuesday. That’s true. But that’s a commodity, and I consider commodities to be external to happiness, not a symptom or a part of it. That said, you can’t probably get a lot of your friends together at 430 am on a Tuesday because they work the day after (and we all have those important meetings) and also they live in the Upper West Side or Williamsburg and you’re in Prospect Heights and it’s not worth the trip. Solution: order Korean-Mexican food to make yourself happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 things europeans need to know before moving to New York</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/10%20things%20europeans%20need%20to%20know%20about%20NYC/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/10%20things%20europeans%20need%20to%20know%20about%20NYC/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;New York is NOT an hedonistic place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;New York does sleep. Quite a lot, actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;New York is the ultimate accelerator of careers and passions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can live without partying until the next morning, number 3 might be worth staying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’re by yourself. You’ll realize you’ve been guided all your life. You’ll get enormous satisfaction in building your own narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’ll be judged on what you do, on what you bring to the table. Own it, and you’ll find happiness in doing that, and maybe a sense of purpose you lacked before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your intimacy is yours. It is not expected that you share things that are truly personal. It is embarrassing and you will not get the feedback you expect. Your problems are yours and you’re expected to deal with them on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guys and girls are not friends. If you’re going to a show, get a coffee, eat together, have a drink or talk about something together, that’s a date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should buy yourself a bike as soon as possible. Not having to take the subway will change your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never take it personal and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The strangely important case of the death of an introvert</title>
      <link>http://www.franc.ly/articles/Death%20of%20an%20introvert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.franc.ly/articles/Death%20of%20an%20introvert/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Aaron dead. World wanderers, we have lost a wise elder. Hackers for right, we are one down. Parents all, we have lost a child. Let us weep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a good chunk of the past weekend obsessed with the case of Aaron Swartz. I couldn’t help to read every bit of news, every opinion, every blog post he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His story is a tragedy from any point of view. A young, uncannily brilliant individual whose irreverence scared the shit out of established powers. Since last year, he was being brutally prosecuted for allegedly illegally downloading millions of academic papers from the MIT system into his laptop, supposedly with the intention of distributing them freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaron was 26 years old when he took his life. He had struggled with depression for a very long time, and a process that was going to cost him millions of dollars that he didn’t have and potentially tens of years in jail pushed that depression to a limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaron Swartz was as committed to the idea of free information as one can be. He was prodigious from an insulting young age and he could have transformed his genius and drive into money with ease. But he wasn’t interested in that. All the projects he ever engaged in seemed to be for a greater, better idea he had of society and he only wanted to work to get there.
aaronswartz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point in the century we have to understand one simple thing about young culture. It is not 20th century young culture. This century works differently. This means no more Sid Vicious, Jimi Hendrixs or Kurt Cobains. Music stopped creating ideological revolutionaries a long time ago. This does not mean that youth has stopped driving change and disrupting thought, culture and art. But we may have to look in places that are not music to find role models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although he took his own life for a combination of reasons we’ll never know about, there was a naivety and extreme idealism in his approach to life. Being idealism a sort of optimism, I can’t help but feeling a painful contradiction in Swartz case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Death%20of%20an%20introvert/aaronswartz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aaron Swartz&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>